Okay, we're starting the
programming course, but
before we get into the nitty-gritty of programming,
let's talk a little bit about the topic of
evaluation.  I think I'm
going to give you some good news in this regard,
but we'll see.  Good.  Hey, what was I
going to tell you?
Uh, no documents.
Ah, no, I have to clone.
Okay, let's go with the documents.
Let's go,
shall we?  And I go to documents.
Everything I'm going to tell you and everything I
'm going to write is
going to be public documents, okay?
So, I mean you can
check them at any time.
So, let's talk about
evaluation criteria.
pund evaluation criteria
Obviously,
well, let's see that
the professional modules
are
structured
into
units and subunits.
This means that
there will be an exercise at the end, not of each
day or each week, but at the end of
each unit
and there will be an exercise at the end of each
subunit.
This means that, for example,
okay, calculation
in, I don't know, in databases, for
example, let's see, we
give databases first.  There are seven,
for example,
in databases
there are seven teaching units.
If in each unit there are about six
If in each unit there are six subunits,
then there will
be
seven unit exercises
and there will be
7 * 6 which is equal to I don't know.
7 * 6 42
subunit exercises.
Obviously,
obviously
the subunit exercises are
simple, but not because I say so,
but because that's what they cover, okay?
They cover little content and there will obviously
also
be seven unit exercises.
Wait a minute.
Yes. Hello.  What's up?
Yes.
Oh,
okay, I don't remember, but I have it
written down.
Yes,
okay, okay.
Wait a moment, just a moment,
just a moment, because of course, I'm seeing that I
don't have you on WhatsApp and therefore I don't
have her saved on WhatsApp.  Okay, no
problem.  I think the password is eh
tame all caps a 2 3
Yes,
you have it in front of you.  Oh, okay, okay.
Yes. And then dollar.  Yeah, but just in case you brought it with you
.
I'm pretty convinced I put
that one in.  Try it.  And if not,
Yes, yes, yes.  Correct.
No, no, no, no.  Enter that password and
you'll see how you get right in.  Okay, come on.
Thank you.  Until now.
Okay, so
the subunit exercises will be
pretty straightforward.  The unit exercises
will have an intermediate complexity
and then there will be
quarterly exams
where, for example, okay, for a simple
matter of logic, if in the databases there
are six teaching units and there are three
quarters, three assessments,
then they will come out to about two
teaching units per quarter, right?
Therefore, since you will be taking the exam with
two teaching units, the exam
will be somewhat more complex.
And this is what is going to happen
now.   There
won't be any theory in each exercise,
okay?  There is no theory exam.
All exams are practice tests.
All exams are about writing
code.
And how will the code be written?  Well, you
will write the code based on the
information rubric, the
evaluation rubric.  You have to write down the
answers.  We will do drills.
Calm down, calm down.  to exams
or evaluations
based on the
evaluation rubric.
And the evaluation rubric, well, you already
know that it's the one that tells us to
first explain the general concept,
then do a development and give some
code examples.  Then put your
source code there in a big way and then give
a brief conclusion about what we
learned in that exercise, okay?  So
that's what's going to happen in
the evaluation to understand what I've
done up to this point.  Well,
for example, if we were in
markup languages ​​and we've seen a piece of
classification, then I'll take everything we've
done here and do an
exercise.  I'll take everything we've
done in 002 and do an exercise.
We haven't reached 003 yet, but when
we get to 003, an exercise will be derived from 003
, okay?  And therefore, you will have
an exercise for each one, for each one is
here,
for each
teaching unit, for each teaching subunit
and, of course, then you will have the
evaluation in the exam, okay?
Just like in previous years,
anyone who knows me from
previous years,
the only secret to testing
this cycle is writing code, right?  It is
doing the exercises.  If you do the
exercises,
you're sure to pass the exam, okay?
If you do all the
unit and subunit exercises I
'll be sending, you don't have to
worry about the exam, because you'll
definitely pass it.
Anyone who doesn't do the
unit exercises and their
teaching units, well, I can assure you
with a fairly high level of certainty that that person
won't be prepared to pass the
exam, okay?  So, you'll
probably
receive
the link this weekend and be able to access the
markup language subunit exercises 001: classification
and 002: characteristics.
And next week we'll continue with
markup languages ​​with 003, 004, 005,
006. And when we've covered all
the subunits of a teaching unit, I'll
give you the exercise
corresponding to that unit.  Before, it
's obviously impossible, okay?  So that's
it, just with
markup languages.  This weekend you will
have a couple of exercises to
do.  That said, let's get into
the subject of programming.
In the subject of markup languages,
well, in the end you'll see that the
markup language, as much as I like
Markup, but the
king of markup languages ​​is HTML.  There is no other
alternative to making web pages.  In
programming things are different because
there are many programming languages ​​that we
can use at any given time.  So
what I usually do in this case
every year is go to the Tob index
and see which programming languages ​​are the
most popular.  And we see
that currently with 25%
almost 26% popularity we have
Python.  Then we have C++ and C, then
Java, then C#ARP, right?  And then other
languages.  What languages ​​are we going to
learn in this order?  Let's learn
Python first.  Python has to
be clear and then C++ C Java as
time goes on.  By the way,
we'll learn JavaScript in markup languages
, okay?  But
in this case I am referring to the subject
of programming.  This is Python.
So, as you can imagine,
this is the reason to learn Python.
That is why the
programming language of choice for
this subject has to be Python.
Then we also have C++ and C, right?
Java doesn't because it's in decline,
so we can't learn a
language that's in decline.  Okay, so
for that, first of all, we're going to
start with the programming language,
and for that, first of all, in terms of
structure and building blocks,
we're going to look at how to get started with Python.
To do this, I recommend that you
first go to momentín, where are you?
Here you go to, uh, sorry, python.org
and on python.org ORG, you download the
latest Python that's available right now, whatever it
is, I don't care.  In this case, I'm
seeing how in the
downloads section, we'll see that we have Python 3137 as of today.
Okay, you can download it now.
You can download it now.  So, once you've
finished downloading it, you
can then install it directly.
Careful, wait a moment, I'm going to make a note of
something.  Go downloading it.
Okay, just a moment.
Hey, python download
pun MD.
Okay, the download website
is https/python.org,
okay?  what is that website there, downloads.
And there you go to download
the latest version
that is available at that time for your
operating system, obviously.
Now, important caution, Sandro,
when you start
the installation in Windows,
check the box
to add
to the Windows AP, okay?  That is very
important.  On Windows only, it
asks you on the first
installation screen and also check
install for all
users, okay?  That's not going to
hurt anyone.
So make sure, make sure you check
these two options.
Once you have it installed,
wait for it to finish installing and
all that.  Yes, but no.  You think
you have one user, but there
are always more on your Windows machine.  There is some
guest user.  Just in case, mark them
all.  Okay?  So, the idea is
that once you have it installed,
you'll see that you'll press the
start button in the start menu and
look for a program called IDL.
When you search after you've installed
Python, of course, when you search for the
program called Idle, you'll find this
cross here, this cross that I'm
showing, and that will give us access to open
the Python code editor.  Okay?
So, I'm going to open it up
and what we're seeing is the
Python shell.  And the Python shell allows us to
start new programs.  It's like a
kind of interpreter.  Everything
we do inside Python will end up being
executed here inside.
Once you open the Python shell
later on, I think I
mentioned this in the previous lesson,
I'll tell you that you can use any ID
you want, okay?  You can use any
development environment you want.  I'm
going to use Idel simply because it
's the default one, it's the one
Python recommends.  But a
typical question from these first sessions is,
hey, can I use
Microsoft's Visual Studio Code?  Yes, you can
use it.  You can use whatever
you want, okay?  I use Idle simply
because it's the default,
okay?  And now what I'm going
to do next is I'm going to press file new
file, okay?  I run file new file to
create a new file.
A window opens with a new
file.
And before I do anything else, what I'm going to
do is I'm going to save it.
Where am I going to store it?  Well, that's the
question, okay?
Hey, I'm going to recommend that from
now on you start creating a
folder structure with everything we're
going to do in the cycle.  And
obviously I recommend that you
use the same structure as me.  The
structure I use is the
structure given by the
cycle regulations, which doesn't
mean anything.  That is, we
can modify this structure, we can
customize it to our liking, but if
the training cycle regulations indicate
that syllabus, then I create this
folder structure, okay?  Ultimately, each of you
, uh, create the
folder structure you want, but it's not a
bad idea to use the same structure
as the cycle, okay?  Seivas,
I'm going to
I'm going to bar, I'm going to W. HTML Dam.
First programming,
structure identification, exercises.  Okay.  And here I'm going
to save 001
output.
exit point python
and here inside, well, I'm going to make
the font size bigger so you
can see me better.
Okay,
now I see
and here inside,
inside this file,
I'm going to
simply write print hello
world
from Python.
And this is our first
Python program.  As with Mark, it's
impossible to make a simpler program
than this.  One of the main reasons
why Python has become
the most popular language is
precisely because of its simplicity, right?  It is
precisely because of its ease.
So now I come over here and
then I save and then,
attention everyone, then I run
module, that is, I run the program.
Yes, it also has its possibilities, but
believe me, before its possibilities,
which it has and many, it is because of its
simplicity, okay?  Because it's one of the
very few programs that you
programming languages ​​where you open a
blank document, write a line and that's it.
And that's a program.  So I go to
Roun, I go to Roun Module and in the
interpreter, okay?  This is the code
you execute and this is the result of the
execution of your code.  And
obviously in our case what
happens is that it tells us, if you
told me to print Hello World from
Python, in the console, in the interpreter,
I print Hello World from Python.
Okay, this was clear.
We have worked with exits.  An output
is when you make a computer program
that writes something to the screen,
right?  That's why it's called an exit because it
comes out towards you.  Let's talk about how we
also have inputs in Python.  What is
an entry?  002
Python input.  By the way, I think
you've noticed that every time I
write code, I name it
sequentially.  001 002 003. Okay, my
recommendation is that you do the
same, because if you write
new files sequentially, you're
creating a kind of
code library, but if you're
constantly hammering and hammering and
hammering the same file, at the end of
the afternoon you only have the latest
version, but you don't have everything that
came before.  So,
basically, one piece of advice I'm going to give you
quite a few times in this course is to do the
same thing as I do.
and that's it.  Okay, if you see that I
do something, you see that I
came here and in my case, obviously I already
had the folder structure created,
you create the
folder structure.  If you see me making
sequential files, you make
sequential files, okay?  Whatever you
see me do, you do the
same, to the extent that you
can.  Clear.
Okay, let's talk about inputs, and if
print is the main command for
input,
input is the command, sorry, for
outputs, I meant.  Input is the
command to make inputs.  Enter
your name.
While print
introduces an output.
Now I'm going to ask you your
name.
Input sets an input.  Print.  And
now, now I know your name,
so I save.  Surcharge.  Now I'm going to
ask you your name.  Enter your
name.  José Vicente.  Now I know your
name.  Okay, this is a way out.  This
requires an entry from me as a human being
.  And this is already a new departure.
So in this way, so in this
way we can now start
writing small programs.  Let's
look at a very interesting resource within
Python, which is
doc string comments.   It
is generally a very good habit
when we start a program to put
quotes, quotes, quotes, quotes, quotes
, quotes.  Not like the
open quotes from before in
markup languages, right?  These are simple quotes,
typical quotes and typical classes of a
lifetime.  And I say, this is a
doc string comment
and you can put as many lines
as you want.
If I run,
if I save and run, nothing's going to happen
because a comment is just a
block of text that a human being can detect
, right?  that a human being can
read.  The machine completely ignores the
comment, it does not interpret it only for
humans.  There are also 004
one-line punpython comments.
And now what I'm going to
do next is put a hash mark and with the
hash mark I'm going to put this is a
one-line comment and that's it.
Okay, then,
well, I run, by the way, okay?   I
run it and we can check how
the content appears.
Okay,
next, next
we're going to talk to finish this
first block
about
what structure
a perfect program, a
beautiful program, should have.
So for that
I'm going to 005
structure
of any program,
recommended structure
of any program.  Python
when I start a program
I do this and I do this.
Wait a moment.  I'm going to write, I'm going
to write a Markdown format
and this out.
Okay.
Recommended structure
of pund programs.
So when we write a program
first at the very top, we need to
create a doc string.
A doc string
is a description
of
the program's title, author, and a
brief summary of what it does.
This is going to be the title of H1.
Essential parts
of a program.  And this is H2.
Done.  Oh,
okay.
Hey, this is this and this is this.
Imports will come next
.
We import the
necessary libraries or import
existing code.
in other files.
Often a software project
is not composed of a single
code file, but rather there are several files that
are composed of each other.
Once we have done this,
we will have the declaration of global variables or
parameters
, to which you will say,
what is a variable?  Well, notice that
subunit two is variable, okay?
So now I will explain what a variable is
and how to
create variables.
Its scope will be global within the entire
program.  It's too early to
talk about what the scope is right now, but I'll
tell you.
Once we have declared variables, we
now
declare
all the functions or classes that the
program uses.  Once again I'm going to put
function classes.
This is this
and this is
global variables.
And this is level two.  And this is
level two.
Okay,
let's create the necessary classes and functions
.   I
know you're probably saying, "But what is a
class and what is a function?"  Well,
we're not there yet.  We're
half an hour into our first day of class.  I'm
just writing this down and I'll teach you everything during the course
, obviously.  Good.  And
finally, the
main method or function, which is the
execution point
from which the program starts.
And this is what we are going to do.  This is
the essential structure that
a program should have later on.  When you know
more, you will obviously skip this
scheme.  When you are an expert, you
take this scheme and do with it
what you want.  But when you do
n't know how to create programs yet and you say,
"Wow, where do I start
now and what parts should my
program have?"  Well, these are the parts
that a program should have.
Once this is said, from
there we are going to start working with
the specific elements of the
programming language and therefore
now next we are going to go
to the second teaching subunit called
variables.  Once again, once again, once
again.
Okay, when the time comes,
when the time comes,
when the time comes, I'll go to
programming,
structure and fundamental blocks,
compress
desktop.
I'm going to go
for artificial intelligence.
and I'll say, put an exercise for my
students on the contents of this
compressed file.
But the exercise has to be about
football,
okay?  If any of you have told me
that your hobby is football, I don't know.
No, let's see, just a moment.
No, we haven't seen any variables yet,
we've only seen what you have
in the compressed file.  Yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes.   It's that
later I'm not going to use GPT chat, that
is, later I'm going to use another
Chinese artificial intelligence called Quen.
So, I'm just doing a
conceptual proof so you guys can
understand what's going to happen later,
okay?  But yes, but you really need to
specify a little more,
okay?  And for example, for
example, do an exercise that shows
a welcome message to the match on the screen
, that writes the names of the
two teams facing each other, that
directly shows the score of the goals and
that writes a final message with the
final phrase of the match, thank you for
attending.  Okay, so you can
use that and the student only has to use
the print command to do this
exercise, okay?  things like this.  This
exercise, for example, this type of
exercise is what we will find at the
end of didactic safety number
one, which is the fundamental block structure
.  And so it's an exercise
that you'll have to solve and that you have to
hand in and all that.  Okay, let's
continue.  Let's continue and in the
next units, stay calm because
we'll do simulations and I'll show you how to
fill out the code, okay?  and all that and
hello.  Yes, no, I've already
prepared it.  Yes, yes, yes, yes.  What's up?
I know, I know, I know, I know.  It's my thing.
It's my thing.  As soon as I can, between today
and tomorrow I will activate it for you.  Yes,
okay.  To you so far.
Let's see, Jonathan.  Uh, let's see, uh,
today's classes, uh, end at 7,
okay?  Today's events can be
viewed starting at 8, eh, I don't
know.  I mean, I mean, this is the same
as last year.  So, I'm
going to show you how I do
things.  I really don't think so after 8
, okay?  Because I think it will
cost YouTube a bit to encode the
video and above all, now as
soon as you finish, I mean, I
'm with you here now in
markup languages, programming and
databases, but then the
second ones come next with
access to data and processes and services,
okay?  So what I'm going to do is
this.  Okay, just a moment
and Darío, okay?  And okay, okay, okay,
perfect, perfect.  Dario, you are
welcome.  Okay, I have places here,
I'm in an office, okay?  And here
I have places for whoever wants to come and
if a lot of you come, well, we'll move to a
classroom and there's no problem, there
are classrooms here too.  Yes, the code, yes,
correct.  But effectively the code,
that is, as I write,
effectively I am going to do it like this.
Where?  Here.  I'm going to do it like this.  Well,
documents or I upload the evaluation criteria now
and indeed, but
clearly, I'm going to do here on 25-26 and
everything I've written, I'll
commit and push and you automatically
have it.  So, that's it, of course.
So,
then I come here, I go to
Tame and then, of course, I'll enter
Tame's YouTube channel and I'll do
the whole process.  I'm going to get it, where
are you?  Here I'm going to take
the personal folder.  I'm going to grab
the last video, okay?  What is this one
here?  Careful, not this one, I mean,
not this one below, because it's the current video,
but I'm going to take the previous one
and upload it,
okay?  and I take it and upload it.
But of course, the point is that
I then take the video, add it to it, and
watch for a moment.  Well, I add it to DAM 1
markup languages, it
's not made for kids, one two 3 and
hidden
and that's it.  Okay?  And it's simply
that, it's simply from then on
the time it takes YouTube to
encode it.
Yes, yes, that's what I'm telling you, I
mean, what I want to tell you is that I don't
have precise control over that
encoding process and there are times when
I find that a half-hour video
is encoded in the next half hour
and there are other times when I
find that it takes until the
next day.  So, that's why I'm telling you that
just like GitHub, I can
guarantee that you can hit commit and you're done
, but YouTube,
unfortunately, can't.  By the way, today
I have this and here, ah, okay.  Now at the
beginning of databases I will take a
short break to help Alicia and
Pilar get into English.  In fact,
in fact, we might have to,
well, or I move Alicia, I don't know, I'll
see.
But okay,
of course, I move when I ca
n't move.   Let's
see, now,
well, now I'll see.  Now I might have to
send an email to the students because we
both co-ordinate here and we can't
use the same room, okay?  But hey,
no problem, we're doing fine now.
The thing, the thing, uh, we were in
Python, okay?  And now we're going to start
working with variables.  To do this, I'm going to
create a new file and let's see
exactly what a variable is.
I come this way
and now I'm going to save this.
I have to go back to the folder.
variables.  Okay, so what is a variable?
A variable is a container of
information.
So I, for example, come and say
age equals 47 and that's a
variable.  If I now want to print the
result,
okay?  It doesn't give me any results, I say
print
age
and we see how on the one hand I declare the
variable and on the other hand I print the
value of the variable.   I
can create as many variables as
I want.  For example, eh several variables
punh
age equals 47, name equals
José Vicente.
And then here when I print I
can chain.
My age is
print age.
print.
My name is
print
name.
We execute.  My age is 47 years old.  My
name is José Vicente.
When Ah, to execute the code there are
two options.  One is to manually go to the
run module menu and that's it.  Or, as
we're seeing here, the hotkey is
F5.  So, since you're going to do this
an incredibly large number of
times, many times with F5 we'll
finish sooner, okay?  And we're going to run
the code better.
Good.  And now, and now next,
uh, next what I want, let's see, wait
a minute, I'm thinking,
okay?  Okay.  Well, what I want to do is
talk a little bit about the rules for
declaring variables.  So,
eh 003 declaration rules
punh
age
is correct.
My age is correct.
My gu under age
is correct, but my space age is not
correct.  I try to run and get an
error.  So this is not correct.
And my
age script is not correct either because the
script in Python is used to work
with numerical subtraction.  Therefore, it is
like saying that I am younger and that would also be
wrong.   I
can say age 2 equals 47, but I
can't say age 2 equals 47
because that would give an error.
Variable names can contain numbers.  In
fact, look, e2 dad is equal to 47.
is also valid.  That is, starting from
the second character I can put a
number, but I cannot put a number
immediately after.
Good.  And and and
Okay,
okay,
we have this over here and then
in variables
we're going to talk about data types, okay?
Data types
are a special characteristic of
variables
that tells
us that each variable can
have a different type of information.
For example, I say name
is equal to
José Vicente.
Uh, age, that's a
string variable.
Age is equal to 47. It
is an integer type variable.
Height is equal to 1.78.
This is equal to eh a decimal.
Ah.  Hm.  I don't know.  Know?
Handsome equals true.  That's a
boolean variable.
A boolean variable
is a variable that is either true or
false, right?  It only runs one bit.
From here there is
the option to convert
data types, because, for example, I should not
perform
numerical operations with things that are not strings.
Let's see.  002,
implicit data type conversion
dot p.   I
come over here and say, uh, age equals
47, but I'm going to do it wrong, I'm going to
do it with a chain.
I'm going to say what the type of
age is.
It's a hello type.  Okay, fantastic.  Print
is of type
string.
One way I have to convert
and convert the data, okay?  It's the
following.  I'm going to print age
multiplied by 2,
okay?  And it says, instead of 47 * 2, it says
47 * 40, that is, 47.
What he has done is chain.
Chain it,
okay?  So I'm going to say age equals
age multiplied by 1.
And now I print print age multiplied
by 2. Wow, it tells me the same thing.  Okay, let's
wait a minute.  Age by one.
Okay.  He tells me the same thing.
An implicit conversion
of the data should have been made here.  Now, there is a much
better explicit conversion
of the data
and then
I say age equals intad.
I'm telling you age was a string,
but now I'm telling you age is an
integer.  I'll change the data type for you
.  And now this is treated as
multiplication.   I
execute.  Oh, wait.  Age multiplied
by 2. Ah, age here.
Okay.  47.
But once I convert it to an
integer, it now runs as
what it's supposed to run.  Okay,
so now, next,
now next we're going to see,
we have data types.  Let's talk
about literals.  The literals, let's
see it here.
literals
string literals
dot Python
and just tell you this is a literal
F5 will tell me OK.  Okay,
sure, this is a literal.
I run it and Python says, "Okay, so what?"   That is
, a literal is a string that
a human enters, a piece of
information that a human enters,
and we often enter it to
title things, print, and
so on.  That is, it is not wrong for the
programmer to introduce literals.   We
just need to know that the system
can then perform operations with
literals, numeric literals
punh and here I'm going to put 47
F5 and the program says, "Okay, then 47,
whatever you want."  I mean, but 47, what
is it?  Is it a variable?  Is it an expression?
No, at the moment it is a literal, it is a piece of information
that, excuse the redundancy,
a human being has literally entered and that's it.
Okay,
sure, eh, with the literals,
obviously, now next we'll
do things.  Let's talk first,
before doing things and before doing
exercises, let's talk about the
vital signs.
So 001, constants
shouldn't change,
but in Python there are no
real constants.  Okay, sure.  Exact.  It's
literally that.  I mean, it's just like you
just said.  You say 47 to Python
and Python says, "Okay, I heard you
say 47, but I'm not doing anything right now
. Maybe later I'll take your 47 and
do something with it."  Okay, but it's like
Python says, "I'm looking at you, but I'm looking at you."  I
mean, I'm sticking with what you
wrote, but I don't know how to interpret it right now
, okay?  Which doesn't
mean it's wrong, it doesn't mean it
's a mistake.  Okay?  So, as far
as constants go, we've seen that
variables can vary.  Look, age
equals 47.
So I say, eh, print
I have rise, I have age, years
and that's it.  F5 I am 47 years old, but
now I say age equals 48. I
just changed the value of a
variable, but nothing happens because
that's what it's a variable for and that's it and
nothing happens.  Now,
the value of a variable can be varied.
Now,
if I say pi, it's a
good habit, a good practice to
write constants in capital letters,
okay?  Lowercase variables
are lowercase
and constants are uppercase.
pi is equal to 3.141.
Sure, eh, I put print.
The value of pi
is
pi, right?  F5.  If I want to save the
value of pi it is 3.141.
Now I come and say pi is ig to 4.
mistake.  In other
programming languages ​​it gives an error.  Not in Python.
Okay, so it says the value of pi is
4. But of course, what happens?  That 4 is not
the value of pi, that is, 4 is nothing
really.  Okay?  So here I'm going to
put it works,
but it shouldn't happen.  That is, you should not
modify the value of a constant
once you have declared it.
When you create a program, you basically
have to ask yourself
whether a piece of data is going to change or not
.  Whether it will change is a
variable.  If it's not going to change, it's a
constant.  Okay, here we go.
Let's go there and then we'll go to
operators and expressions, okay?  And with
that we will finish this first part of
programming for today's class.  We'll take
a short break and now we'll
continue.  Okay, let's go
to operators and expressions.  There
is a lot to discuss here.
Operators and expressions, exercises.  And I
'm going to start by saying, introducing two
arithmetic operators
punh
and then I say eh print
4 + 3. Arithmetic operators
allow us to do addition.  4 + 3 7 print 4 - 3 4
- 3 1 print 4*ado 3 print
4/
3 and finally print integer module of the
division between 4 and 3 which will be 1. The
arithmetic operators, which are these
characters here, basically what they
do is
addition, subtraction, multiplication,
operations,
that's why they are called operators.
Next we move on to the
comparison operators.
So it is true that
4 is less than 3. It is not true, it is
false.  It is true that 4 is less than or equal
to 3. It
is not true.  It is false.   It is
true that 4 is greater than 3. It is
true, it is true.  And it is true that 4 is
greater than or equal to 3. It is not equal, but it
is greater.  which is true.
Is it true that 4 is exactly the same
as 3?  It's not true, but it is true that
4 is not the same as 3. It's true.
Comparison operators do not perform
specific arithmetic operations, but
rather perform comparison operations
whose result is either true or false.   We
also have the 003
abbreviated arithmetic operators.
So if age equals 47 and I
want to add 5 years, there are several ways
to express it.  One of them is age
equals age + 47. That form is
valid, but the mathematical operator
expressed, that is, sorry, oh, I wanted to
add five, right?  47.
The abbreviated mathematical operator is age
plus equals 5. Below is equal to
above.
Now
I say age equals age - 5. Age
minus equals 5.
Age equals age multiplied by 5.
Age multiplied equals 5. I think
you're more or less getting how it works.
And age is equal to age divided by 5.
Age divided equals 5. We execute.
Well, and then we would have to print.
Okay, I'm going to print age.
Print print.  As you can see, as you're
seeing, it's obviously the first day, of
course it is, okay?  But Python almost
seems like a toy language, right?  It's
a language that when you write it's like
Markdown, right?  The same reason
I like Markython.
And it's a language that you say,
gosh, it's impossible for it to be
easier than this.  There are many other
languages, some of which make it much more
difficult, not with bad intentions, there is an
explanation for that, but Python is
oriented and focused on being the
simplest language you can imagine.
Okay, let's see more operators.  So
there are other operators that are the
boolean
punh and these are practically the
last ones that I'm going to explain in theory,
okay?  And now, after this
short break, since we've
polished up the subunit a bit—no,
sorry, unit one—we'll start
doing exercises, and I'll also give you
a run-through of how the
exercises are delivered, okay?  This way you can rest
assured that the system is
designed to make things easy for you, not the
other way around, okay?  I mean, I'm not going to
make your life difficult, I have no
need to make it difficult in life.
I want you to program, that's all I
want.  For this, I will make an
effort to teach you.  You are
going to make an effort to learn, and in the
effort that I teach you, I will
try to make things as easy
as I know how.  Okay?
Then I told you, I told you that eh, I'm going
to go this way and say, it's true
that it's true that 4 is equal to 4 and that
one of the two boolean operators is and
and that cu and that 3 is equal to 3,
sorry, and that 2 is equal to 2. It's true,
but
Ah, no, no, no, no, no, calm down,
calm down, it has nothing to do with it.  Now,
now I'll explain it to you later.  It makes no
difference whether you have Windows, Mac or
Linux.  You will be able to deliver it
exactly the same.  The
delivery form will be fully compatible
with the delivery.  You'll see.  I'll
explain it later.  So, eh print.
Now, is it true that 4 = 4 and 3 = 3 and
2 = 1?
Well, it's not true because 4 = 3.
Agreed.  4 = 4. 3 = 3. But it is not
true that 2 is equal to 1. Now, is it
true that 4 is equal to 4 or that 3 is equal to 3 or
that 2 is equal to 1. Yes, it is true because
as it is the OR operator, this is true.
This is true.  Then the whole expression
is true.  Now I copy and paste.  Is it true
that 4 is equal to 4, that 3 is equal to 2 or that 2 is
equal to 1?  It continues to be true because it is
true that 4 is equal to 4. And finally,
print.
Is it true that 4 is equal to 3 or that 3 is
equal to 2 or that 2 is equal to 1?  It isn't
true.  Okay, this can't be true anymore,
obviously, and so it tells me
false.
Now the return.  Let's take a 10-
minute break.  I'm going to leave this
open, but I'm going to get up.  Okay, I
'll be back in 10 minutes.  Now,
next we're going to do a mock
exercise, okay?  And you'll see how to
develop and submit a
course exercise from 0 to 100. Don't worry,
you'll see it's easier than it
seems.  Once you get the hang of
it, it's the same mechanics for the
entire course, so don't worry, you'll
see how cool it is now.  Hey, I'll
take this opportunity to stop recording.